Guide to the Robert L. Patten: George Cruikshank research materials, 1792 - 2002, bulk 1836-1977 MS 493
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series V: Manuscripts, correspondence and other materials by and about George Cruikshank, circa 1811-1976, 234930; (30 boxes)
  - Sub-Series D: Ronald Searle, circa 1826-1892, 235055
    - Printed materials, broadsides, invitations, pamphlets, and clippings, 1853-1875, undated, Searle 690-697, 235057 (Box 105, Folder 30-37)
    - Card files, typed cards and slips with descriptions of the C.C. Kohler and Ronald Searle collections, 235056 (Box 106)
  - Sub-Series E: Other bookseller collections: Wilson, Benjamin, Carnegie, Edwards, Mott and Richards, Lyrle Fletcher, Bradburn, and Frognal, 1823-1893, 235004
    - These collections, from various booksellers, include autographs, engravings, bills, envelopes, draft letters and completed letters, advertsements, catalogs and other ephemera. Transcriptions of the Wilson collection can be found in the Oxon, England file, box 42, folder 12., 235054
    - Wilson:, 235053
    - Cruikshank autographs, undated, Wilson 1, 235052 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Bills from Cruikshank to J.C. Bowles and J.A. Sleap, 1849-1856, Wilson 2-5, 235051 (Box 107)
    - Engraving of George Cruikshank, engraved by C.E. Wagstaff, signed by Cruikshank, undated, Wilson 6, 235050 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Envelopes and and I.O.U. from Cruikshank, 1866, undated, Wilson 7-9, 235049 (Box 107, Folder 7-9)
    - Draft letters from George Cruikshank, unknown correspondents (anon), 1827, 1867, Wilson 10-11, 235048 (Box 107, Folder 10-11)
    - Draft letter from George Cruikshank to Sergeant Major Spooner and Lieutenant Troene(?), 1868, Wilson 12, 235047 (Box 107, Folder 12)
    - unspecified, 235046 (Box 107)
    - Letters from George Cruikshank, M-Y, 1828-1875, Wilson 63-84, 235045 (Box 108, Folder 1-22)
    - Bills addressed to Cruikshank, 1823, 1856, Wilson 85-86, 235044 (Box 108)
    - Letters to George Cruikshank, 1814-1845, Wilson 87-90, 235043 (Box 108, Folder 25-28)
    - Prescription, 1877, Wilson 91, 235042 (Box 108, Folder 29)
    - 2 letters from George Percy Cruikshank to Ross, 1879, undated, Wilson 92-93, 235041 (Box 108)
    - Letter from George Percy Cruikshank to Clement Scott (?), 1893 November 16, Wilson 94, 235040 (Box 108, Folder 34)
    - 3 letters from Robert Cruikshank, one to unknown recipient, others to Mr. Oxberry and Mr. Winston, 1823, undated, Wilson 95-97, 235039 (Box 108, Folder 35-37)
    - Bill from Marsh (?) Robinson to I. Robert Cruikshank, 1823 October 17, Wilson 98, 235038 (Box 108, Folder 38)
    - Letter from Henry Blackwell to Mr. Delaford, reference to Cruikshank, 1891, Wilson 99, 235037 (Box 108, Folder 39)
    - Benjamin:, 235036
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to John Thompson, undated, 235035 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Carnegie:, 235034
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to Mr. Ling, 1873 December 22, 235033 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Edwards:, 235032
    - Letter from George Cruikshank, unknown recipient, 1863 August 20, Edwards 1, 235031 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to Dr. West, 1843 March 30, Edwards 2, 235030 (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - Mott:, 235029
    - "Mr. Cruikshank Testimonial, " circa 1873, 235028 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - Richards:, 235027
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to F.W. Cosens, 1866 September 5, Richards 1, 235026 (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to S. Phillips Day, 1872 September 29, Richards 2, 235025 (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to Mr. Hogarth, 1853 February 4, Richards 3, 235024 (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to Mr. Jerdan, 1851 March 23, Richards 4, 235023 (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to Charles Kent, 1871 January 1, Richards 5, 235022 (Box 109, Folder 10)
    - Draft letter from George Cruikshank to R.E. Lofft, undated, Richards 6, 235021 (Box 109, Folder 11)
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to Dr. Muspratt, 1867 January 28, Richards 7, 235020 (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to John Noble, 1864 January 11, Richards 8, 235019 (Box 109, Folder 13)
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to Mr. C. Pollard, 1864 August 20, Richards 9, 235018 (Box 109, Folder 14)
    - Carnegie Book Shop:, 235017
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to "Dear Joe," regarding money matters that must remain private, 1859 April 9, 235016 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Frognal:, 235015
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to the director of the Liverpool Institute, 1867 February 20, Frognal 1, 235014 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Draft letter from George Cruikshank, unknown recipient, draft letter from Cruikshank to the editor of The Times, and a printed letter to Cruikshank from Henry Thomas, Shakespeare Ter-centenary Monument Committee, 1863 July 13, undated, Frognal 2, 235013 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - Kyrle Fletcher:, 235012
    - 2 letters from George Cruikshank, to Mrs. Octavia(?) Blewitt, 1875 August 4 and to George Mills, 1861 August 1, Kyrle Fletcher 1&2, 235011 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to B.W. Ball, 1864 February 22, Kyrle Fletcher 4, 235010 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Bradburn:, 235009
    - Fragments, Bradburn material, includes letter extracts, signatures, advertisements, and other ephemera, 1858, 1884, undated, 235008 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Profile portrait of Robert Cruikshank by F. W. Paithorpe, undated, 235007 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - Letter from F.W. Paithorpe to Mr. Brewer, with sketch of a face, undated, 235006 (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - Pencil sketch, with title and signed by Cruikshank, "Old Sydney Gardens Bath," undated, 235005 (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Series F: Miscelleanous papers, correspondence, objects and ephemera, circa 1823-1905, 234935
    - Correspondence, primarily to George Cruikshank unless otherwise noted:, 235003
    - Adshead, J., 1846, 1847, 235002 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Ainsworth, W.H., circa 1842 (also includes a letter from Ainsworth to Macrone, undated), 235001 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Auldjo, John, 1861, 1867, 235000 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Baldwyn, C., 1823, 234999 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Barker, M.H., 1843, 234998 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Bates, William, 1876, 234997 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Blanchard, L., undated, 234996 (Box 111)
    - Bogue, D., 1848, 234995 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - Brother, D., 1863, 234994 (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - Brough, R.B., 1857, 234993 (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - Clarke, 1824, 234992 (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - Cox, W., 1851, 234991 (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - Dey, William, 1850, 234990 (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - Farish, W., 1866, 234989 (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - Gouoling, S., 1857, 234988 (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Greville, 1869, 234987 (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - Hotten, 1860, 1864, 234986 (Box 111, Folder 17)
    - Hunt, Robert, 1865, 234985 (Box 111, Folder 18)
    - Jackson, John, 1839, 234984 (Box 111, Folder 19)
    - Linton, W.J., 1867, 234983 (Box 111, Folder 20)
    - Mackenzie, R. Shelton, 1847, 234982 (Box 111, Folder 21)
    - Martin, John, 1838, 234981 (Box 111, Folder 22)
    - Mayhew, Horace, undated, 234980 (Box 111, Folder 23)
    - Mayhew, K., 1851, 234979 (Box 111, Folder 24)
    - Merle, W.H., undated, 234978 (Box 111, Folder 25)
    - Mills, G., 1865, 1866, 234977 (Box 111, Folder 26)
    - Morson, Jr., undated, 234976 (Box 111, Folder 27)
    - Pickering, B.M., 1861, 234975 (Box 111, Folder 28)
    - Prince, J.W. (?), 1855, 234974 (Box 111, Folder 29)
    - Purvis, J.W., 1840, 1841, 234973 (Box 111, Folder 30)
    - Reach, Angus, undated, 234972 (Box 111, Folder 31)
    - Roscoe, T., 1831, 234971 (Box 111, Folder 32)
    - Russell, E., 1871, 234970 (Box 111, Folder 33)
    - Tegg, Thomas, 1829, 234969 (Box 111, Folder 34)
    - E.J.P., 1847, 1848, 234968 (Box 111, Folder 35)
    - 2 letters to George Cruikshank, sender unknown, 1838, 1846, 234967 (Box 111, Folder 36-37)
    - From George Cruikshank to:, 234966
    - Bradbury and Evans, 1868, 234965 (Box 111, Folder 38)
    - Cruikshank, Eliza (Mrs. Cruikshank), 1858, 234964 (Box 111, Folder 39)
    - Kent, W.C.M., 1852 December 27, 234963 (Box 111, Folder 40)
    - 2 letters, to Tilt and Bogue, 1842 September 2 and to "My Dear Lord," 1869 September 11, 234962 (Box 111, Folder 41)
    - Letters to and from George Cruikshank regarding the "Omnibus," 1841-1861, 234961 (Box 111, Folder 42)
    - Letter to the editor, The Times, 1865, 234960 (Box 111, Folder 43)
    - Other correspondence:, 234959
    - Letter signed by Mary Cruikshank, 1829 April 9, 234958 (Box 111, Folder 44)
    - A.G. Stark to Robert Cruikshank, 1848, 234957 (Box 111, Folder 45)
    - R.S. Bell to P. Cruikshank, 1852, 234956 (Box 111, Folder 46)
    - G.A. Beckett to Evan, 1852, 234955 (Box 111, Folder 47)
    - R.J. M Douglas to "Dear Sir," 1905, 234954 (Box 111, Folder 48)
    - Miscelleanous correspondence, includes a note from Mrs. Cruikshank to Mrs. Dickens, 1868, 1869, undated, 234953 (Box 111, Folder 49-51)
    - Drawings and sketches:, 234952
    - "Comic Almanak," loose plates, covers (Bradburn notes), undated, 234951 (Box 111, Folder 52)
    - "Miser's Daughter" illustrations, [1842], 234950 (Box 111, Folder 53)
    - Pencil sketches, undated, 234949 (Box 111, Folder 54)
    - Drawing from Scraps and Sketches, part 2, [1828], 234948 (Box 111, Folder 55)
    - Sketch of a church, signed by George Cruikshank, undated, 234947 (Box 111, Folder 56)
    - "What is a Flame," with sketch, circa 1875, 234946 (Box 111, Folder 57)
    - Printed materials, receipts, advertisemtents and other ephemera:, 234945
    - Accounts and recipts, 1835, 1847, 1855, 234944 (Box 111, Folder 58-59)
    - Notes, drafts and addresses relating to "Lord Bateman," "A Pop-Gun Fired Off," address regarding "teeth," circa 1860, 234943 (Box 111, Folder 60)
    - Prescriptions and envelopes, 1866, undated, 234942 (Box 111, Folder 61-62)
    - Our Mutual Friend Advertiser, loose pages, [1865], 234941 (Box 111, Folder 63)
    - Signature, Charles Dickens, undated, 234940 (Box 111, Folder 64)
    - Manuscripts and printed material relating to the National Temperance League, Volunteer Corp., and a notice of George and Eliza Cruikshank's silver wedding anniversary, circa 1860-1875, 234939 (Box 111, Folder 65-66)
    - Various lists, signatures, notes, receipts and envelopes, circa 1832-1877, 234938 (Box 111, Folder 67-72)
    - Objects:, 234937
    - Copper plate, wood blocks, coin, and a small wood box with silver inlay bearing the initials "GC," purported to have been given to Cruikshank by Charles Dickens., 234936 (Box 112)
  - Sub-series G: Figurines, 234931
    - Tiny Tim figurine, produced by Royal Doulton, 234934 (Box 113)
    - Scrooge figurine, produced by Royal Doulton, 234933 (Box 113)
    - Oliver Twist figurine, produced by Royal Doulton, 234932 (Box 113)